Hello, and, welcome to build my name is term creates and I'm a product marketer with microsoft
advertising today I'm joined by two engineering colleagues hoosier and
...hi everyone my name is project
...way and I work as an engineer on microsoft ad st case I'm
visit logical pollen emma group program manager in microsoft ads working on monetize a shun
...promotion and today we're going to talk about new tools for app developers to
help you monetize and promote your app with ads.
Advertising delivers tremendous value for app developers in fact it's
a source of nearly one-third of all revenue for
developers in windows store in addition monetize a shun with microsoft
advertising has improved significantly year-on-year the top ten apps
are generating nearly seventy percent more revenue this year compared to last year today
we're going to do a deep dive and to tools video interstitial and app promotion
hoosier what-you taken away with the to interstitial is crm thanks cover
video interstitial ads are great opportunity for app developers industry
wide video interstitial cp m are much higher than standard banner ads
integrating these ads can help boost revenue in your app in addition
video interstitial as can be integrated during the natural pauses in your game-playing which
protects the user experience some app developers even integrate rewards
based advertising where people received benefits such as a new game life by watching
...ad in terms of availability
we're excited to announce the windows stand preview...at client...case
supports video interstitial is since the...ad sdk.
Video interstitial...will be...across phones tablets nbc's.
Later this summer we release and add...
which supports video interstitial on windows and windows phone a dot one.
It's easy to get started with video interstitial ads and let me show you how to integrate these
...in your app in just five simple steps...we have here is a
sampled universes windows platform uw the app on windows
stan...and csharp code behind.
The integrate interstitial video ads step one is to install the advertising
...which is available as a direct download
...reference...app in the code behind and
...reference to microsoft advertising without dui.
Step do is to instantiate the interstitial ad.
Give it a name.
The next step is to reflect the...in my sample app I have a button which
...request the...
Request attics and three parameters the at...which in my case is video.
My application id.
And, the ad unit id which I would define in my app.
Before coding show...wire up the...
The first event is the...very event.
Which is fired when the ad is ready to be shown after it has been requested?
The next event is the completed event.
Which is fired if the user what is the entire ad to completion?
In the event handler and go to allow the user to move on
to the next level in your scenario after the ad has completed which in my
sample app would simply means stopping the...down timer.
The next event is the...event.
Which is fired if the user backs out while the added still playing?
And, the last event is the error
...event which is the name suggests is used to handle error scenario.
Even...show on the...
In your app be shirts checked the user state before calling
...in order to avoid any interference with the natural flow of your
...for demo purposes only
...call show in the ad ready event handler to watch the...
Check the at state.
That's all there is to integrate interstitial ads let's run the app and what's the...
In my sampled the user is out of lives and to
move on to the next level has to wait for about ten minutes
however the user can skip to the next level right away by watching...
Dui let's, you know, you're watching the...timer shows how long the video is.
It may or may not contain
...url which opens up in the browser.
And, back button which we let the user navigate back to the app I have now watch the
...and I can move on to the next level.
To recap the five steps step one is to install the atis dk and
add a reference instantiate the interstitial ad wire up
the for events we fetch the added and call show...the...that's fantastic no
...you have any best practices for developers when integrating these video interstitial
ads yes we do try to find natural breaks in your
game associate ads with tangible upside such as between game levels or
...in your app wire up to for events that are available in the interstitial
ad class we fetch the add to...any weight times fantastic
...developers find to the latest artistic case the ads
...website which is
ads in apps dot microsoft dot com please remember the windows
...preview is available today and later this summer we will offer a
release ready version on windows stan...interstitial solution on windows
and windows phone a dot one fantastic thank you project now let's turn it over to
vj to talk about our new capabilities with respect to app promotion fantastic
...promotion is better than ever the first announcement that I wanted to make is a
promotion is available from...center
dead-center easier one-stop-shop to monetize and to promote your apps so,
we made it available from...so as soon as you publisher app you can promote your app
...with in-depth center second we've added some
great targeting capabilities including order targeting based on age gender
and geography so by default all of your apps are auto targeted
...opted in for audio targeting second we also have some fantastic feature to
tracker installs and understand your you user acquisitions so this is
all available today I also want to remind you that one of the easiest way to
tryout app promotion is using the cross promotion capability it comes to free
of charge you can if you have more than one app you can cross promote your other app using
cross promotion functionality I'm also super excited about us summer release we're working
very hard to launch a bunch of additional targeting capabilities but also working
with external measurement companies to enable third-party app install tracking for
developers finally the app promotion capability will be expanded to many more
new markets and we will also be increasing the budget campaign budget for
you so to summarize you can get started in three easing steps first
constructor ad using these visit big intuitive tools we provide a bunch of creative tools for
you to constructor ad design easily and quickly second send your targeting whether you
...for manual targeting or in
the leverage the default order targeting capabilities set
...parameters and finally measure,
measure install look at the user acquisition and
optimize your campaigns let me show you how easy it is to promote your app right with in-depth center.
...the new windows to centerfold
...one-stop-shop to monetize...promote your ass.
You can see all...assume campaigns are...the page
...possible of your under enacted and house...slap you
...in-house can section moi.
This convert.
Since is a moi.
I'm going to target in this case this app is to a talking to us
enormously as.
Using...
...design.
Since is an you...I don't have many gains followers
...astonishment at creative and not going to...
...design shows as a free at the samoa.
Tools to...at.
...the scope...image moi published to the
...interest part of meta...
...in order to getty iphone of the audience you can select
question on that.
This...the targeting section microsoft automatically targets
...audience for your hat...
In case you need to you choose the tide audience you get
to select gender and each inverse...page manatees.
Inverse scenario I'm going to say
...functionality choose...microsoft exclusion...the monkey much.
Since I had unloading
...other microsoft...my credit card ahead use automatically gets
here in case I need to use a new credit card I can select
...up management...credit card.
Individual...going to use existing
...been...microsoft on a transaction.
This is...
Summer ...a...targeted to listing yet.
Selected automatic commenting functionality to that microsoft choose a targeting
You see...at...
That's go ahead and conform this...
Behind-the-scenes yellow creating and the at...
This our campaign will be created...
and will also be...the next ten minutes and other...you?
...this transaction to complete what.
Is completed...see this as processing for a few seconds
after crossings...use rate...
Let's look at how to measure and optimize you install.
Once the app camping is running you can look at how happiness performing by looking at the
capping...
Here you get to see that
happiness performance based on the exposure office carrying to the total number of
...it looks...result today as well as install.
Using these metrics you can...campaign and
...having...effectiveness so to summarize in order to
...uses you can you can start trying
...campaigns gives your feedback.
We've been working that bunch of early adopter partners one of our early adopter
partners random salad games...leveraging the
promoter app capability from diffs interest less from...center and they
have experience fantastic use of acquisitions and installed in fact very recently
when they launched
a new app the promoted the app using that promotion functionality that
resulted in fantastic success for them so, it also working with many of the early adopter partners
andthey've...the similar results as well fantastic, you know, I love the
...targeting feature could you explain how it works
here's order targeting by default optimizes
...targeting parameters based on the...install base so you don't have to
anything all the developers of by default opted into the order targeting functionality
free of cost that's great now it's also great to see that you can
...app motion campaign right with
in-depth center whatever plans in terms of advertising capabilities within...center so we on
...adjoining this many capabilities that exist today or moving towards moving into
dev center and as you can see promoter app all of the capabilities of
promoted app is available that in-depth center similarly for monetize a
shun they're working hard to more all the reporting capabilities also to
...so will be sharing more details about the
...integration later this summer fantastic thank you vj and
...you project we invite you to learn more check out
microsoft advertising build blog for summary of everything
...announcing it build in addition we invite you to visit the as an apps website as
...microsoft-dot-com or go directly to dead-center and launch...app
promotion campaign today thank you and have a great build thank you thank you?